（マイト･ガイ）ハア ハア ハア
ハア ハア…
はっ！
あっ！
ハア…
He was formidable.
強敵だった
I'd expect no less of
my imposter.
さすが俺の偽者
（日向ひゆうがネジ）フウ…
（テンテン）うっ ハア ハア…
I did it...
やった
（ロック･リー）ハア ハア…
ハア ハア ハア…
Yes!
押忍！
ハア…
Everyone!
Have things been settled?
みんな 片づいたか？
Yes, Guy-sensei!
（リー）はい ガイ先生！
（ネジ）ああ
（テンテン）当然！
- Yeah...
- Naturally!
よし！
All right! Now we head off to
back up Team Kakashi!
じゃあ これより
カカシ班の援護に向かう！
- Roger!
（３人）了解！
（チヨ）ああ ああ…
（チヨ）うっ！ ああ…
（春野はるのサクラ）あっ！
（チヨ）ああ…
Grandmother Chiyo!
チヨバア様！
（チヨ）うう… ああ…
Grandmother Chiyo...
（サクラ）チヨバア様…
ああ… うう…
I'm not surprised...
（サクラ）無理もない
Sasori's poison could knock her out
at any moment...
サソリの毒で いつ
気を失ってもおかしくないのに…
We've finished what
we were supposed to do.
あたしたちの
やるべきことは終わりました
すぐにでも里に戻って
解毒しないと！
We need to return to the village
and neutralize the poison immediately...
ハア ハア…
それよりも わしにはまだ…
More importantly, I've still got...
something I must... do.
やるべきことがある
It's probably... that powerful will
that's keeping her conscious...
（サクラ）たぶん…
その意思だけで意識を保ってる
ハア ハア ハア…
But... what is it she has
to go this far to do?
（サクラ）でも ここまでして
やらなきゃいけないことって…
（チヨ）うっ ああ…
I'm sorry...
すまない
Here we go!
行きます！
（デイダラ）ついてきてるな… うん
They're following me.
フフ…
Shall we do this?
（はたけカカシ）やるか…
Naruto.
（カカシ）ナルト！
（うずまきナルト）ん？
（カカシ）少し離れてろ！
Get back... a little.
Got it.
分かったってばよ
Mangekyo Sharingan!
（カカシ）万華鏡写輪眼まんげきょうしゃりんがん！
♪～
A voice heard in the distance gives me a hint.
tooku de kikoeru koe wo hinto ni
One by one like-minded people are standing up.
hitori mata hitori tachiagaru doushi
Lets overturn all the everyday, monotonous things.
kurikaesu dake no fudan doori kutsugaesu
I'm ready, are you ready?
junbi iize are you ready
A shiver spreads through my body, violently ringing stomping.
karadajuu furuwasu shindou ni hageshiku uchinarase yo stomping
Constantly stirring in me, it calls me.
taezu tsuki ugokasu call me
Catching that unchanging, never wavering story, Come on!
kawarazu yuru ga nutsukamu story come on
Everybody stand up! Today's the best time to get up!
everybody stand up agero kyou ichiban no jikan da
Before my eyes you still don't stop, speed hunter.
me ni mo tomaranu speed hunter
Everyone is a victim to that attraction, Yeah! (Come on!)
daremo ga mina toriko kanban yeah come on
Everybody Hands up! It's the highly anticipated Hero's Come Back!
everybody hands up matashita na hero's come back
Hold up your fingers and count down.
zujou kazoe yubi oru count down
Let's go, 3-2-1 make some noise!
ikuze 3-2-1 make some noise
Are you ready for a few risks?
hey yo whoa tashou no risuku wa kakugo desho
You have to get up no matter how many times you fall. (Get it on!)
nanka korundatte tatsu get it on
It's not some conspiracy, just a paper-thin session
nare ai ja nai ze kami hitoe no sesshon
The pent up feelings turn into a crystal.
irikunda kanjou kidzukiageta kesshou
The rising cheers will become your courage.
wakiagaru kansei ga yuuki tonaru
So stand up now, no matter how much pain you feel.
tachiagareba ima ijou kurushimi tomonau
But in the end I'm sure you'll laugh.
soredemo saigo wa kitto warau
Everything will be swept away in victory and cheer.
subete sarau shouri to kansei
Everybody stand up! Today's the best time to get up!
everybody stand up agero kyou ichiban no jikan da
Before my eyes you still don't stop, speed hunter.
me ni mo tomaranu speed hunter
Everyone is a victim to that attraction, Yeah! (Come on!)
daremo ga mina toriko kanban yeah come on
Everybody Hands up! It's the highly anticipated Hero's Come Back!
everybody hands up matashita na hero's come back
～♪
Hold up your fingers and count down.
zujou kazoe yubi oru count down
Let's go, 3-2-1 make some noise!
ikuze 3-2-1 make some noise
Kakashi Enlightened!
Mangekyo Sharingan!
（カカシ）万華鏡写輪眼！
ああ…
ん？
あっ！
What is... this?!
なんだ これは？
A Visual Jutsu...?!
（デイダラ）瞳術(どうじゅつ)？
しまった！
Oh no!
あ？
What is this Jutsu...?
（ナルト）なんだ？ この術ってば？
すげえ…
It's amazing...
You won't get away!
（カカシ）逃がすか！
（デイダラ）うう… クソ！
Damn it!
（かかし）うっ…
（デイダラ）わあああ…
うう…
（カカシ）クソ…
Damn it...!
My arm's getting sucked into space...?!
（デイダラ）
俺の腕を空間ごと… なんて術だ！
What kind of Jutsu is this?!
（デイダラ）ぐあああ
（カカシ）うっ…
（デイダラ）うう…
（カカシ）ああ… ハア
（カカシ）外した
I missed...
（カカシ）うう…
I guess I still can't control
the location or size
（カカシ）まだ
結界空間の位置と大きさが
うまくコントロールできないか
of the dimensional barrier very well...
だが…
But I won't... miss next time...
次は！
ああ…
（カカシ）ああ… ハア…
（デイダラ）うわっ
（カカシ）ああ…
（デイダラ）うわあ
うう…
（カカシ）ハア ハア…
ハア ハア…
クソ！ 逃がしたか？
Damn it! I let him get away!
ハア… 振り切れたか
I shook him off, huh?
ハア…
あっ！
うわっ！
（ナルト）螺旋丸らせんがん！
Rasengan!
（カカシ）よし！
All right!
（デイダラ）うっ！
影分身かげぶんしんの術！
Shadow Clone Jutsu.
あっ 我愛羅があら！
Gaara!
（カカシ）ハア ハア ハア…
（ナルト）我愛羅！ 我愛羅！
Gaara! Gaara!
（ナルト）カカシ先生 大丈夫か？
Kakashi-sensei, you all right?
（カカシ）ああ なんとかな
Yeah... somehow...
（ナルト）我愛羅
今 出してやっかんな！
Gaara. I'll get you out now.
うっ… 我愛羅！
Gaara!
ここを通ったようじゃな
It looks like they came through here.
はい　恐らくは
連れ去られた我愛羅君を追って
Yes. They were probably going after
Gaara who was taken...
うっ… てめえ！
You jerk...!
おい 我愛羅！ 聞いてんのか！
Hey! Gaara! Are you listening?!
いいがげんにしろよ！
Knock it off!
（カカシ）やめろ ナルト！
（ナルト）ぐっ…
That's enough, Naruto!
（カカシ）分かってるはずだ
You should know...
そうそう　分かってんだろ？
That's right. You know, don't you?
とっくに死んでるってな うん
He's been dead for a while.
（チヨ）急いでくれ！
（サクラ）はっ！
Please hurry.
はい
Right!
苦しくなったら教えてくださいね
Please let me know if
it gets too painful.
ああ
I will...
リー！
Lee...!
（リー）もたもたしてると
置いていきますよ テンテン！
I'll leave you behind if
you drag your feet, Tenten!
何 言ってんの！
What're you talking about?!
あんたたちが追いつくの
待ってたんじゃない！
I was waiting for you guys to catch up!
そうでしたか
I see. Naruto and the others
should be expecting us
では ナルト君たちが
僕たちの合流を期待してるはずです
to rendezvous with them.
急ぎましょう！
So let's hurry!
えー
What? We should wait
for Neji and Guy-sensei...
ネジとガイ先生を待ったほうが…
（リー）テンテン それなら大丈夫です
We don't need to worry about that.
（テンテン）あ…
Huh?!
（ガイ）遅いぞ リー！ テンテン！
You're late, Lee, Tenten!
まっ…
Oh! It's your fault
they got ahead of us, Tenten!
テンテンのせいで
抜かれてしまったじゃないですか！
（テンテン）こら！
Hey! Hold it, Lee!
待ちなさいよ！ リー！
（ガイ）カカシ 聞こえるか？
Kakashi! Can you hear me?
Hey, Kakashi!
おい カカシ！
やはり 無線は届かんな
Just as I thought.
The radio isn't working.
ネジ カカシたちの状況は
どうなっている？
Neji, what's happening with Kakashi
and the others?
暁あかつきとは いまだ交戦中のようだが
It looks like they're still fighting
the one from the Akatsuki...
風影かぜかげの奪還には成功したようだ
But it seems they've succeeded
in retrieving the Kazekage...
しかし…
However...
しかし？
However?!
（ナルト）我愛羅…
Gaara...
（ナルト）あっ！
我愛羅！
Gaara!
おい！ おい！ 我愛羅！
Hey... Hey, Gaara!
くっ… 我愛羅！
Gaara!
（デイダラ）だから言っただろ
I told you, didn't I?
He's already dead.
もう死んでるって
風影を餌に人柱力じんちゅうりきをおびき出すって
アイデアまでは よかったんだが
It was fine using the Kazekage
as bait to lure out the Jinchuriki.
計算外は…
But I didn't plan on...
あいつが ついてきたことだな うん
him coming along...
左腕は…
My left arm...
砂瀑柩さばくきゅう！
Sand Prison!
（デイダラ）砂の人柱力に潰されたし
was crushed by the Sand Jinchuriki,
and even my right arm, too...
右腕まで…
これじゃあ 術も使えねえ
Now I can't even use a Jutsu.
これまでか…
I guess this is it...
しかし イタチ並みの瞳術を
使うヤツがいるとはなあ
But... I never thought there was anyone
with Visual Jutsu as good as Itachi.
この人柱力は 大したことねえ
This Jinchuriki's nothing special.
それより問題はカカシだな うん
Kakashi's the more important issue...
ブン殴ってやる！
I'll pound you!
（デイダラ）分かった 分かった
Fine, fine.
近いうちに
また相手してやるよ うん
I'll take you on again one of these days.
（カカシ）油断しすぎだよ
You let your guard down...
（デイダラ）ん？
しまった
Oh no!
（ナルト）うおーっ！
よっしゃあ！
Yes!
（カカシ）だから 言ったろ！
I told you that you let your guard down...
油断しすぎだって
影分身の術！
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
（デイダラ）うわー！
うわっ
（ナルト）だあーっ！
（殴る音）
（デイダラ）うっ… あっ！
ナルト…
Naruto...
やあーっ！
う…
（カカシ）うっ…
（ナルト）はっ！
（カカシ）粘土？
It's clay... Was it a Substitution?!
変わり身か？
（ナルト）ぐ…
くくっ…
（カカシ）あれは！
That's...!
♪～
Just like always.
daitai itsumo doori ni
As I turn that corner.
sono kado wo magareba
I am lost in the waves of people.
hitonami ni magire komi
Melting, disappearing.
tokete kiete iku
I lose my way.
boku wa michi wo nakushi
I even completely lose my words.
kotoba suranaku shite shimau
But just one thing.
dakedo hitotsu dake wa
Remained, remained.
nokotteta nokotteta
Your voice.
kimi no koe ga
Your smiling faces, your angry faces, everything.
warau kao mo okaru kao mo subete
Keeps me walking on.
boku wo arukaseru
Surely, when I see the point where the clouds have broken.
kumo ga kireta saki wo mitara kitto nee
You know what I mean?
wakaru desho
nee wakaru desho
～♪
Next Episode
ハンカチを用意しろ！
Get a handkerchief ready.
次回は 涙なくして見られない
怒とうのクライマックス
The next episode features
a raging conclusion
that will leave you in tears.
遠方からバカ弟子を案じる
わしの磨き抜かれた先見の明が
I show great concern for
my foolish pupil from afar.
My finally-honed foresight will save
Naruto with the power of love!
ナルトを愛の力で救うのだ
あっ！ それ俺も１枚かんでるから
師匠２人の愛ってことにしてください
Oh, I'm involved in this too,
so make it the love of
his two  masters that saves him.
では 次回のサブタイトルは
Then how about,
"Love Saves the Foolish Pupil"
愛はバカ弟子を救う
でどうだ？
for the title of
the next episode?
さすが 自来也じらいや様
それでいきましょう
Excellent, Jiraiya-sama.
Let's go with that.
いいよな ナルト？
You're okay with this,
right, Naruto?
いいわけねえだろ！
Like hell I am. No thanks!
Aesthetics of an Instant
お断わりだ！
— Leaf Ask-Us-Anything Investigation Team!
（サクラ･ナルト）
木こノ葉は なんでも調査隊
"Leaf Inquiry Division"
皆さんの いろんな疑問に
お答えします
We'll answer any of your questions.
きょうの疑問は これ！
This is today's question!
What's under Kakashi Sensei's mask?!
（ナルト）
カカシ先生のマスクの下って
どうなってんだ？ コレ？
やっぱり みんな気になるみたいね
Sure enough, it seems
everyone's wondering about that.
俺らも昔 調べてみたことがあるんだ
We also investigated that back in the day.
ラーメンをおごって
We treated him to some ramen
食べるところを
見ようとしたり
and tried to see under his mask
while he ate.
"Operation Ramen"
FAILED
（サクラ）後を
つけたりもしたわね
And we tried following him, too.
Operation Follow Him
FAILED
（ナルト）
お風呂にまで
He even wears his mask
when he takes a bath.
マスク
着けてるんだもんな
Operation Baths
（サクラ）
ほんと変な先生よね
He's really a weird teacher, isn't he?
FAILED
（ナルト）
最後は変装して
And lastly,
we all wore disguises
and tried attacking him, but...!
Last Resort
みんなで
襲ったんだけど
Use of Force!
（サクラ）あっさり
やられちゃった
He kicked our butts just like that...
（ナルト）
ダハハハ…
"FAILED"
（サクラ）結局 カカシ先生が
In the end, Kakashi Sensei
自分から取って
見せてくれたんだけど
actually took off his mask on his own
and showed us, but...
（ナルト）なんと…
Believe it or not,
what he had underneath...
その下にあったものは…
マスクの下に
またマスクって…
was yet another mask...
Talk about a total fake out...
どんだけ肩透かしよ
でも 俺たちは
まだ諦めちゃいないぜ！
But we won't give up yet!
Someday we'll expose his real face!
いつか先生の素顔を
暴いてみせるわ！
Stay tuned for more information!
続報に
期待してくれよ！
FIRST QUESTION:
KAKASHI'S TRUE FACE
CONTINUING INVESTIGATION